<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.locolust.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.locolust.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-23T05:14:19+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Locolust</title><subtitle>On locolust.com, I am taking you on my personal journey through the world.</subtitle><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><entry><title type="html">High Altitudes and Holy Sites: A Birthday to Remember in Bhutan</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/bhutan/high-altitudes-and-holy-sites-a-birthday-to-remember-in-bhutan" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Altitudes and Holy Sites: A Birthday to Remember in Bhutan" /><published>2024-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/bhutan/high-altitudes-and-holy-sites-a-birthday-to-remember-in-bhutan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/bhutan/high-altitudes-and-holy-sites-a-birthday-to-remember-in-bhutan"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-mysterious-beginning">A Mysterious Beginning</h2>

<p>The excitement of an unknown destination can stir a unique blend of nervous energy and exhilarating suspense. That was precisely what I was feeling as we approached the airport early in the morning. It wasn’t until we stood before the Druk Air counter—the national airline of Bhutan—that the puzzle was completed. Druk is the thunder dragon, a symbol of Bhutan, and not “just a local name for Bhutan”, as I falsely state <a href="https://www.sleepless.sg/17">in my podcast</a>.</p>

<p>Nat, ever the orchestrator of surprises, had outdone herself by booking us on a business class flight aboard a tiny, specially modified A319 Airbus. This aircraft, adapted for the unique challenges of Bhutan’s mountainous landscapes, was our chariot into the unknown. The check-in process was quaint, reminiscent of a bygone era where boarding passes were handwritten and check-ins were managed against a physical list by a kind but firm attendant.</p>

<h2 id="the-flight-into-the-mountains">The Flight into the Mountains</h2>

<p>The flight itself was a preamble to the uniqueness of Bhutan. The <a href="https://simpleflying.com/bhutan-paro-airport-exclusivity/">approach to Paro Airport</a> is notorious among pilots; it’s a thrilling dance between the clouds and mountain peaks, requiring a sharp weave through the valleys. Only a handful of pilots are qualified to navigate this treacherous path, making each landing an act of precision and bravery. As we descended, the landscape embraced us—towering mountains on either side, guiding us to the runway.</p>

<p>Sadly, the Himalayan peaks were shrouded in clouds on our arrival, but the dramatic descent was an adventure in itself. Touching down on Bhutanese soil felt like stepping through a portal into another world—a theme that would continue throughout our visit.</p>

<h2 id="a-quiet-welcome">A Quiet Welcome</h2>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paro_International_Airport">Paro Airport</a> was unlike any other I’d experienced. Its architecture was more akin to a temple or a fortress than an airport, adorned with intricate wooden carvings and paintings that celebrated Bhutanese culture. Stepping inside, the ambiance shifted dramatically to a quiet, almost reverential silence. It was an airport, yes, but it felt like a sanctuary.</p>

<p>Our guide, Nima, and our driver, affectionately known as Uncle Wanchuk, greeted us with traditional silk scarves and a local rice wine served from a wooden flask. The drink was unique, setting the tone for the culinary adventures that lay ahead. It was here that we first noticed a peculiar local habit—the chewing of betel nuts, which left many with stained, red teeth.</p>

<p>(Here’s an unrelated but interesting <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/style/taiwan-betel-nut-beauties-constanze-han/index.html">article</a> about betel nut girls in Taiwan.)</p>

<h2 id="the-drive-to-thimphu">The Drive to Thimphu</h2>

<p>The journey from Paro to Thimphu was a visual feast. Bhutan’s pristine environment and the meticulously preserved architecture had a storybook quality to it. We stopped along the way to capture photos of a Dzong, a type of fortified monastery that is integral to Bhutanese culture. The landscape was a vivid tapestry of greens and browns, untouched by the heavy hand of industrialization.</p>

<p>Thimphu itself was a blend of the traditional and the modern, bustling yet orderly. The local people were reserved but friendly; their smiles were rare but genuine, reflecting a society that values depth over ostentation. Dinner at <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Zombala2/">a local restaurant</a> introduced us to momos—dumplings that were a delightful mix of flavors and textures, paired with surprisingly tasty chili-seasoned fries.</p>

<h2 id="a-morning-of-mysteries-and-monasteries">A Morning of Mysteries and Monasteries</h2>

<p>The calm after a night’s rest in Thimphu was short-lived, as the anticipation of exploring more of Bhutan woke us early. Our breakfast, though not extraordinary, was the simple fuel we needed before meeting our guide, Nima and Uncle Wanchuk. They were ready to show us more of this enigmatic country, starting with a visit to another dzong.</p>

<p>Driving through Thimphu, we encountered a sight that was uniquely Bhutanese—the city’s main intersection. Remarkably, it had no traffic lights. Instead, a policeman directed traffic from a beautifully decorated booth. It’s said that Thimphu is the only capital city in the world without traffic lights.</p>

<h2 id="the-challenge-of-altitude">The Challenge of Altitude</h2>

<p>Our first major hike in Bhutan began at an altitude of about 2,800 meters, climbing to 3,569 meters. For someone not accustomed to such heights, the hike was a breathless endeavor. Despite the physical challenge, the destination was worth every step. We reached a monastery that was both architecturally and spiritually profound, adorned with golden Buddha statues and vibrant wall paintings. The offerings at the altar—ranging from bottles of milk to cigarettes—were as eclectic as they were sincere.</p>

<p>Descending from the monastery offered some of the <a href="https://www.bhutaninbound.com/blog/2020/10/04/lungchutse-hike/">most breathtaking natural scenery</a> I have ever witnessed. The forest was a patchwork of needle trees, unlike the tropical jungles of Southeast Asia, interspersed with bright rhododendron flowers and small clearings where the sunlight broke through. The tranquility of the forest and the beauty of the trail were almost surreal, reminiscent of a scene from a fairy tale or an epic like “Lord of the Rings.”</p>

<h2 id="local-life-and-culinary-discoveries">Local Life and Culinary Discoveries</h2>

<p>Later that day, we had the privilege of staying with a local family. This intimate experience offered us a window into the everyday life of the Bhutanese people. The lady of the house prepared a variety of dishes, including what they referred to as Bhutanese pizza—a delightful creation with a rice base, topped with eggs and greens. We also tasted the national dish, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ema_datshi">Ema datshi</a>, chili cheese, multiple times. It’s a simple yet flavorful dish that can be quite potent depending on the cheese used. We didn’t become fans.</p>

<p>Our afternoon continued with a visit to a site housing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/108_(number)#Buddhism">108</a> stupas, reflecting the spiritual numerology significant in Buddhism. The setting was picturesque and peaceful, perfect for reflection and appreciation of Bhutan’s spiritual heritage.</p>

<h2 id="cultural-immersion-and-reflections">Cultural Immersion and Reflections</h2>

<p>The following day was filled with more cultural immersion. Entering a dzong (fortresses), you’re immediately struck by the ornate detail: every inch of wood has a story, carved into it with a precision that speaks of centuries-old traditions. The architecture of these dzongs incorporates large, multi-storied courtyards and temples, interconnected by a series of staircases that seem to wind endlessly upward. Each step brings a new angle from which to appreciate the fortress and the sweeping views it offers of the surrounding valley.</p>

<p>The dzong’s prayer wheels add an auditory and tactile dimension to the visual splendor. These wheels, large and small, are often arranged in long rows, each embossed with ancient mantras. Turning these wheels as you pass by is not only a spiritual act, meant to disseminate blessings and peace, but it’s also a moment of connection with the local practices and the devout who have walked these paths before you.</p>

<p>We also visited the longest suspension bridge in Bhutan, which, while modest by some standards, was a marvel in its own right. A highlight of our cultural exploration was an invitation to our guide Nima’s home. Here, we tried our hands at archery, Bhutan’s national sport, and even milked a cow, experiences that were both humbling and hilarious.</p>

<p>Our culinary journey ended on a high note at the <a href="https://www.sixsenses.com/en/resorts/bhutan/lodges/six-senses-thimphu/dining/">Six Senses restaurant</a>, where we indulged in a mix of local and international cuisine, including a succulent fatty brisket and a unique olive oil cake for dessert.</p>

<h2 id="ascending-to-serenity">Ascending to Serenity</h2>

<p>Our journey continued with a morning meditation session in front of a gigantic golden Buddha statue, the largest sitting Buddha in the region. The serenity of the moment, the stillness of the air, and the grandeur of the statue created an atmosphere of profound peace.</p>

<p>The following hike to one of Bhutan’s remote monasteries was unlike any of my previous alpine experiences, such as the leisurely ski lifts of Zermatt. Here, the trek itself was a test of endurance and spirit, markedly different from the mechanical ascent of the Swiss Alps. At around 4,000 meters, the thin air of Bhutan’s high altitudes was palpable, making each step a conscious effort.</p>

<p>Our destination was <a href="https://www.wmf.org/project/phajoding">Phajoding</a>, a monastery perched in the solitude of the mountains, where we were to spend the night. The approach was steeped in the kind of anticipation that comes with entering a sacred space, not just to visit, but to partake in its ancient rhythms.</p>

<h2 id="a-night-at-the-monastery">A Night at the Monastery</h2>

<p>The monastery offered an austere welcome: simple, stark, yet profoundly peaceful. Accommodations were in a guesthouse adjacent to the monastery—a humble structure with just the basics for sleeping, including mats on the floor and a single electrical heater that barely staved off the night’s chill. The simplicity of our lodgings was a reminder of the monks’ ascetic lifestyle, which focuses on spiritual rather than material richness.</p>

<p>Dinner was equally spartan. As evening fell, the monks began their prayers, their chants accompanied by long horns that echoed hauntingly through the cold air. These horns, reminiscent of the alphorns of the Alps but deeply rooted in Buddhist traditions, added an otherworldly quality to the already mystical atmosphere.</p>

<h2 id="engaging-with-monastic-life">Engaging with Monastic Life</h2>

<p>Our involvement in the monastic life, albeit brief, was profound. We joined the monks for evening prayers, an experience that allowed us a glimpse into their daily practices and spiritual dedication. The opportunity to converse with the monks provided insights into their lives, beliefs, and the disciplined pursuit of their faith.</p>

<p>That night, the temperature inside mirrored the near-freezing outdoor conditions, making sleep elusive and the physical discomfort palpable.</p>

<h2 id="leaving-our-mark">Leaving Our Mark</h2>

<p>The next morning, after a challenging night, we participated in a cherished local tradition—hanging prayer flags. This act, symbolic of sending prayers and good wishes on the wind, was especially meaningful in such a sacred space. Climbing a tree to secure our own colorful flags, we left a piece of ourselves behind in this remote corner of Bhutan.</p>

<h2 id="descent-and-return-to-normalcy">Descent and Return to Normalcy</h2>

<p>Descending from the monastery, the landscape shifted. Fewer flowers but a richer tapestry of greens painted a scene straight out of a fairy tale.</p>

<p>Once back at a lower altitude, we indulged in a familiar ritual—sampling local burgers. This return to a more worldly experience was a comforting contrast to the austerity of the monastery. The burger joint, a blend of local and foreign, served up not just delicious burgers but also a Nepalese-style soup that hinted at peanuts without revealing them, rounding off our journey with a taste of the familiar and the exotic.</p>

<h2 id="the-culmination-of-culture-and-hiking-tigers-nest">The Culmination of Culture and Hiking: Tiger’s Nest</h2>

<p>The adventures in Bhutan reached new heights—literally and figuratively—as we geared up for the hike to <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/article/the-tigers-nest">Tiger’s Nest</a>, the gem in Bhutan’s crown of natural wonders. Known officially as Paro Taktsang, this monastery is perched precariously on a cliffside, resembling a scene straight out of a fantasy novel. Often compared to iconic landmarks like the Eiffel Tower or the Statue of Liberty because of its symbolic significance, Tiger’s Nest is a sight to behold and the destination of our most anticipated hike.</p>

<p>The ascent was challenging yet somehow more manageable than our previous treks, possibly due to a combination of acclimatization and sheer excitement. Within about two hours, we found ourselves at the gates of what could only be described as a spiritual fortress. Inside, the monastery was as serene as any other we’d visited, adorned with the familiar sights of golden Buddhas and vibrant wall paintings. Despite its similarities to other monasteries, the setting made it extraordinary. On my birthday, the experience was heightened by lighting a large butter candle, an act that felt both humbling and profound.</p>

<h2 id="a-birthday-among-monks">A Birthday Among Monks</h2>

<p>Later that day, the celebrations took a more personal turn. Dressed in traditional Bhutanese attire, which added an authentic touch to the occasion, we participated in a special birthday prayer and meditation session in a local temple, the <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/abQitGRAMDbCkHqs7">Ugyen Pema Woedling Zangthopelri</a>. This was not an everyday occurrence; sitting at the heart of a Buddhist temple, surrounded by monks in song and prayer, was surreal. The monks welcomed us warmly, sharing in the celebration of my birthday. The first slice of my chocolate cake was offered to Buddha, a gesture of respect and gratitude, before sharing the rest with everyone present. This blend of cultural immersion and celebration was unlike anything I had experienced before.</p>

<h2 id="soothing-traditions-and-local-fun">Soothing Traditions and Local Fun</h2>

<p>The festivities were followed by a unique Bhutanese hot stone bath. This traditional therapy involved sitting in a wooden tub while hot stones were carefully placed in the water, infusing it with heat and herbal essences. The experience was both relaxing and invigorating, perfect after the day’s exertions.</p>

<p>Our evening continued with local dances and a lighthearted performance involving two people dressed as a yak, adding a playful end to our culturally rich day. This blend of traditional Bhutanese entertainment provided a delightful insight into the local customs and community spirit.</p>

<h2 id="reflecting-on-the-journey">Reflecting on the Journey</h2>

<p>On our final day, as we prepared to leave this beautiful country, I reflected on the journey. From the adrenaline of ascending to Tiger’s Nest to the warmth of the local people and the serene moments of cultural connection, Bhutan offered a profound experience.</p>

<p>As we boarded our flight back to Singapore, I carried with me not just souvenirs like the copper Buddha—a quaint reminder of the trip—but memories of a land where spirituality permeates every aspect of life. Bhutan, with its majestic landscapes and deeply ingrained Buddhist traditions, had given me a birthday to remember, filled with lessons in humility, the joy of simplicity, and the beauty of a slower pace of life.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="asia" /><category term="bhutan" /><category term="bhutan" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="paro" /><category term="thimphu" /><category term="culture" /><category term="airports" /><category term="betel-nut" /><category term="landing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The day I discovered our next adventure was cloaked in mystery until the very moment we stepped up to the Druk Air counter. Bhutan was waiting, and it promised a journey as serene as it was steep.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kenya Safari to Dubai City Lights</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/africa/kenya/kenya-safari-to-dubai-city-lights" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kenya Safari to Dubai City Lights" /><published>2024-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/africa/kenya/kenya-safari-to-dubai-city-lights</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/africa/kenya/kenya-safari-to-dubai-city-lights"><![CDATA[<h2 id="an-early-start-to-safari-adventures">An Early Start to Safari Adventures</h2>

<p>Our journey to Kenya’s safari began with an early morning wake-up call at 5 a.m., following the last event of a wedding we were attending. Without the usual morning preparations or breakfast, we quickly left the hotel amidst a minor hiccup with the hotel’s billing system. Our friend Hatim managed to resolve the confusion, allowing us to depart for the train station in Mombasa on time.</p>

<p>The process at the train station was unexpectedly rigorous, resembling airport security protocols with multiple luggage checks. Here, we encountered a small issue with a pocket knife I had in my luggage, which was resolved by Hatim through a small, friendly transaction with the security personnel. An interesting glimpse into local practices.</p>

<p>Boarding the train to Voi, we were pleasantly surprised by its comfort and the level of service, marking a stark contrast to the rugged adventure awaiting us. The journey was smooth, with the train staff ensuring cleanliness and comfort throughout the ride. This train ride, blending modern conveniences with the anticipation of the wild adventures ahead, was the beginning of our unforgettable journey into Kenya’s heartland.</p>

<h2 id="embracing-the-wild">Embracing the Wild</h2>

<p>Our arrival at the safari camp was like stepping into a different world. Greeted with eucalyptus-scented towels and breathtaking views, the camp was a haven in the heart of the savannah. Our tents, luxurious and well-appointed, offered the perfect blend of adventure and comfort. The highlight, however, was the wildlife. From the majestic elephants to the elusive leopards, each sighting was a reminder of nature’s wonders.</p>

<p>The game drives through Tsavo National Park were exhilarating. Zebras casually grazing by the roadside, giraffes emerging from the bushes, and a family of elephants at a watering hole were sights that no zoo could replicate. The vastness of the park, coupled with the diversity of its inhabitants, made each moment unforgettable.</p>

<h2 id="a-5-star-tent">A 5-star tent</h2>

<p>The camp, set amidst the untamed beauty of the Kenyan savannah, offered an unexpected luxury that contrasted sharply with the rugged wilderness surrounding us. Our accommodations, though termed “tents,” were anything but the basic shelter one might expect in the heart of the wild. These tents were spacious, with elegant furnishings that melded modern comforts with the essence of nature, ensuring a stay that was as comfortable as it was authentic.</p>

<p>Upon our arrival, we were greeted by the camp staff with refreshments and cold, eucalyptus-scented towels—a small but thoughtful gesture that was much appreciated after our journey through the dusty savannah. The camp itself was designed to maximize our connection with the natural world, featuring an open dining area where we could dine under the stars and a pool that offered panoramic views of the sprawling landscape.</p>

<p>Daniel, the camp chef, was a character in his own right. With the flair of a seasoned entertainer, he introduced each meal with a short speech, imbuing the dining experience with a sense of occasion. His culinary skills were evident in every dish served, from hearty breakfasts to sumptuous dinners, each meal was a delightful exploration of local flavors and ingredients. Daniel’s presentations added an unexpected layer of enjoyment to our dining experiences, making each meal … wait for it … memorable.</p>

<p>Our days were filled with game drives that brought us face-to-face with the incredible biodiversity of Tsavo National Park. The thrill of spotting zebras, giraffes, and elephants in their natural habitat was unparalleled. The guides, knowledgeable and passionate about wildlife conservation, provided insights that enriched our understanding of the ecosystem and the challenges it faces.</p>

<p>Evenings at the camp were a time for relaxation and reflection. The clear night skies, untainted by light pollution, offered a stunning backdrop for our conversations, with the Milky Way visible in all its glory.</p>

<p>The camp was not just a place to stay; it was an integral part of our safari experience. It provided a comfortable base from which we could explore the wild beauty of Kenya, a place where we could unwind and reflect on the day’s adventures. The seamless blend of luxury and nature, along with the warm hospitality of the staff, made our stay at the camp an unforgettable part of our Kenyan adventure.</p>

<h2 id="were-on-party-safari">We’re on Party-Safari</h2>

<p>Upon reaching Tsavo National Park, we were eager to delve into the heart of Kenya’s wilderness, yet our enthusiasm was momentarily dampened by unexpected complications at the entrance. The park’s procedures, akin to a digital fortress, required online payments that proved to be a hurdle with our non-local credit cards. Despite several attempts across multiple cards, the system stubbornly refused our transactions. This delay, extending over an hour, was a test of patience. Ultimately, through a combination of local assistance and inventive problem-solving, we managed to navigate this bureaucratic maze though.</p>

<p>Inside Tsavo, the inconvenience at the gate quickly faded into insignificance against the backdrop of the park’s stunning landscapes and diverse wildlife. Our first encounters - zebras and giraffes casually grazing, their presence both surreal and grounding, set the tone for the safari. The park, vast and untamed, was a living canvas, each turn revealing new wonders. Elephants, in their majestic tranquility, crossed our path regularly and deer was basically omnipresent.</p>

<p>The safari days were filled with moments of awe and serenity, hand in hand with humorous occations – for example our girls finding themselves in need amidst the vast savannah, opting for the shelter of a roundabout’s center for a brief respite. Check out my Instagram for pix.</p>

<h2 id="a-brief-respite-on-chale-island">A Brief Respite on Chale Island</h2>

<p>After the exhilarating safari experience in Tsavo, our next destination offered a tranquil contrast. Chale Island, a slice of paradise nestled off the coast of Mombasa, welcomed us with its pristine waters and peaceful atmosphere. The island’s unique charm was encapsulated in our accommodation, a quaint tower room that boasted panoramic views of the surrounding ocean.</p>

<p>Our days on Chale Island unfolded in leisurely bliss, with much of our time spent at the resort’s stunning pool which offered an endless view of the ocean horizon. The poolside became our sanctuary, where the hours slipped by unnoticed as we indulged in the luxury of relaxation. The highlight was Kenya’s national cocktail, the Dawa. This refreshing blend of vodka, honey, lime, and crushed ice, served right in the pool, became the embodiment of our laid-back island lifestyle.</p>

<p>As the sun began its descent, we were introduced to the island’s sundowner spot, an experience that was a highlight of our evenings. Nestled on a secluded part of the island, this location featured nets strung over the water, where we could lie back and immerse ourselves in the tranquility of the moment. Accompanied by a selection of snacks and the soft glow of the setting sun, it was a place of pure relaxation and reflection.</p>

<p>Chale Island provided a perfect balance to our Kenyan journey, offering a peaceful retreat where time seemed to stand still.</p>

<h2 id="a-whirlwind-tour-of-dubai">A Whirlwind Tour of Dubai</h2>

<p>Our return journey through Dubai was a stark contrast to the natural beauty of Kenya. The city’s architectural marvels, from the towering Burj Khalifa to the opulent Burj Al Arab, showcased human ingenuity. Our day was packed with sightseeing, from the historic alleys of Old Town to the glittering Gold Souq. The culmination of our journey in Dubai’s bustling metropolis was a fitting end to our adventure, bridging the gap between the serene and the spectacular.</p>

<h2 id="a-long-way-home">A long way home</h2>

<p>The long journey back home offered one last glance at Kenya’s diverse landscapes, a bittersweet farewell to a country that had given us so many unforgettable memories. Before heading to the airport, we seized the opportunity for some last-minute souvenir shopping. It was here that I stumbled upon Master Chum Chum, a quaint wooden carving that immediately caught my eye.</p>

<p>The flight back to Dubai with flydubai fell short of our expectations. A last-minute aircraft change meant that the upgraded seats we had anticipated were replaced with ones lacking the comfort and amenities we had hoped for. This, coupled with the challenge of trying to rest on an overnight flight, added a note of discomfort to our return journey.</p>

<p>Arriving in Dubai, we were determined to make the most of our day-long layover. Despite our tiredness, we embarked on a whirlwind tour of the city’s iconic sights. From the architectural marvel of the Burj Khalifa to the luxury of the Burj Al Arab, and the bustling atmosphere of the Dubai Marina, each landmark offered a glimpse into the city’s blend of modernity and tradition. Our highlight, foodies that we are, was lunch at a renowned ramen spot, where the flavors transported us momentarily back to Asia, a fitting precursor to our return home.</p>

<p>The sightseeing continued with visits to the Dubai Frame and various souks, immersing ourselves in the city’s vibrant culture and history. As the day drew to a close, we found ourselves at the airport once again, this time preparing for our flight back to Singapore with Singapore Airlines. The journey back was a stark contrast to our previous flight, marked by the exceptional service and comfort that Singapore Airlines is known for. Landing in Singapore at the break of dawn, we were home within an hour, a smooth and fitting end to our adventure.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="africa" /><category term="kenya" /><category term="kenya" /><category term="safari" /><category term="tsavo" /><category term="mombasa" /><category term="dubai" /><category term="nightlife" /><category term="wildlife" /><category term="photography" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our adventure, from the untamed wilderness of the safari to the vibrant city life of Dubai, was a journey of contrasts. It taught us the beauty of nature's simplicity and the allure of urban sophistication. From waking up to the serene sunrises over the savannah to navigating the bustling streets of Dubai, every moment was a testament to the diverse experiences our world has to offer.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Kenyan Adventure and a Dubai Detour</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/africa/kenya/a-kenyan-adventure-and-a-dubai-detour" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Kenyan Adventure and a Dubai Detour" /><published>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/africa/kenya/a-kenyan-adventure-and-a-dubai-detour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/africa/kenya/a-kenyan-adventure-and-a-dubai-detour"><![CDATA[<p>Why Kenya, you ask? Imagine receiving a wedding invitation that not only promises love and festivities but also an adventure across continents. That was precisely the case for us when Hatim, Canadian by passport but Indian by heritage and residing in Kenya, announced his wedding. The thought alone was enough to pique our curiosity and set us on a journey from Singapore to the heart of Africa.</p>

<p>(For those intrigued by the intricacies and behind-the-scenes tales of our Kenyan adventure, my podcast “<a href="https://www.sleepless.sg">Sleepless in Singapore</a>” features a <a href="https://www.sleepless.sg/5">Kenya episode</a> where I dive a bit deeper.)</p>

<h2 id="the-journey-begins-flight-frenzy-and-dubai-detours">The Journey Begins: Flight Frenzy and Dubai Detours</h2>

<p>Embarking on this trip was no small feat. Direct flights were a dream too far-fetched, leading us into the labyrinth of flight research — a task I hadn’t tackled in years, thanks to the convenience of Singapore Airlines and my stash of miles. However, necessity reigns supreme, and soon I found myself juggling between <a href="https://www.skyscanner.com.sg">Skyscanner</a> and <a href="https://www.google.com/travel/flights">Google Flights</a>, hunting for the perfect itinerary. Our chosen route? Singapore to Dubai on Singapore Airlines, a brief layover filled with sightseeing, followed by a flight with flydubai to Mombasa, and finally, a domestic hop to Nairobi with Kenya Airways.</p>

<p>Dubai, our layover city, was a blend of opulence and chaos. The vast airport, the cumbersome immigration queues, and the lengthy wait for a taxi contrasted sharply with the welcoming gesture of a free SIM card loaded with data — a small but significant relief for any traveler.</p>

<p>Adding to the mosaic of our Dubai experience was an odd encounter at the <a href="https://www.marriott.com/en-us/hotels/dxbmd-le-meridien-dubai-hotel-and-conference-centre/photos/">Le Meridian</a>, a supposed sanctuary of luxury. Our request for a simple paper napkin to wrap a half-eaten pastry was met with a baffling denial. The waitress informed us, with an air of finality, that taking food outside was against hotel policy, except, inexplicably, for the ill. This small but surreal interaction, far from ruining our mood, added a layer of humor to our layover tales, illustrating that even in the most prestigious of establishments, the unexpected awaits.</p>

<h2 id="kenya-calls-weddings-wildlife-and-wonders">Kenya Calls: Weddings, Wildlife, and Wonders</h2>

<p>Arriving in Nairobi, the anticipation of finally meeting up with Mera and Marty gave us an adrenaline rush. It felt like no time had passed when we saw them waiting for us at the <a href="https://www.glamhotel.co.ke">Glam Hotel</a>. Their hugs were as warm as the Kenyan sun, and the laughter and catching up began immediately.</p>

<p>At this first night we found ourselves at the <a href="https://tamarind.co.ke/carnivore/">Carnivore Restaurant</a>, a place that’s all about the meat. Imagine a barbecue on steroids, and you’re halfway there. This isn’t just any dining spot; it’s a carnivore’s dream come true, where skewers of meat are paraded around as if on a victory lap, each cut more succulent than the last. From the conventional beef and chicken to the more adventurous game meats, it’s an all-you-can-eat feast that tests the limits of your appetite. If you are particulary adventuresome, try the bulls balls. Yes, I’m talking testicles here. (And if you are not: Ask Mera!) The atmosphere? Pure joy and hearty laughter, as we signaled ‘yes’ for more with the drop of a flag.</p>

<p>And at night, Christian and Melina joined the group, injecting fresh excitement into our already vibrant gathering.</p>

<p>The next day, among the myriad of wonders Kenya unfurled before us, a visit to the <a href="https://www.giraffecentre.org">Nairobi Giraffe Centre</a> stood out as a moment of sheer enchantment. Here, in the gentle company of these towering yet graceful beings, we discovered a peculiar marvel: the antiseptic properties of giraffe tongues. As we fed them, their long, rough tongues grazed our hands, a sensation as surprising as it was fascinating. This encounter was not just a brush with wildlife but a lesson in the delicate balance of nature, where even a giraffe’s lick carries the healing touch of the wild.</p>

<h2 id="lessons-in-patience-african-indian-timing">Lessons in Patience: African Indian Timing</h2>

<p>Landing in Mombasa was like stepping into a novel filled with vibrant characters and picturesque settings. The wedding was nothing short of spectacular, blending Indian traditions with African warmth in a celebration that spanned several days. From color ceremonies to henna tattoos, each event was a testament to cultural fusion and familial bonds. Definitely not always on time – but mostly worth our time.</p>

<p>Not all was smooth sailing, however. The concept of “African Indian timing” tested our patience, with schedules stretching and twisting in ways that could frustrate even the most seasoned traveler. Being late for your own wedding? Totally acceptable here. Yet, this too became a cherished part of our adventure, teaching us to embrace the unexpected with humor and grace. I couldn’t help but make light of the situation, joking that “everything is 20 minutes” became our mantra, regardless of whether it was actually a five-minute walk or an hour-long drive.</p>

<p>Our stay at the “<a href="https://sunnsand.co.ke">Sun ‘n Sands Hotel</a>” in Mombasa was an experience in itself. While the hotel was just shaking off the cobwebs of a COVID-induced hiatus, it served as our base for the whirlwind of wedding festivities. It wasn’t just about attending a wedding; it was about immersing ourselves in a vibrant confluence of cultures, a sensory overload that I hadn’t anticipated but wholly embraced.</p>

<h2 id="sailing-into-the-sunset-boat-rides-and-beachside-bliss">Sailing into the Sunset: Boat Rides and Beachside Bliss</h2>

<p>One of the trip’s highlights was a serene boat ride, a moment of tranquility that balanced the whirlwind of activities. As we glided towards the sunset, the worries of the world seemed to dissolve into the waters below, leaving us with a sense of peace and contentment.</p>

<h2 id="a-home-away-from-home">A home away from home</h2>

<p>The climax, however, was our time at Hatim’s home. The warmth and hospitality we received from Hatim’s lovely mom and the whole family were unparalleled. We were treated to an array of Indian dishes that tantalized our taste buds, a feast that felt both exotic and comforting. The color ceremony, a spectacle of hues and laughter, left us covered in shades of joy – and Hatim covered in shades of yellow. The henna ceremony added another layer to this rich tapestry of traditions. Watching the intricate patterns take shape on the ladies’ hands was mesmerizing, a beautiful blend of art and ritual that spoke volumes of the culture we were momentarily part of. These experiences, set against the backdrop of Hatim’s welcoming home, were a poignant reminder of the beauty of coming together, of celebrating love in all its forms, in a setting that was as heartwarming as it was splendid.</p>

<h2 id="15-minutes-of-fame">15 minutes of fame</h2>

<p>Nat had already orchestrated much of the wedding, infusing the events with dances, games, and a whole lot of fun. Yet, it was the evening she stepped up as MC that left me beaming with pride. There she stood, effortlessly navigating the night’s festivities, showcasing a talent I didn’t know of, a talent that seemed second nature to her. She led a Q&amp;A game where the newly weds, Mubi and Hatim, had to match their answers without seeing each other – questions like “Who’s the tougher one?” and “Who’s more romantic?” elicited responses that were both revealing and amusing. Then there was the bingo game, designed to engage everyone in attendance, creating an atmosphere of communal joy and laughter.</p>

<p>Indeed, Nat’s performance was so stellar that I half-joked about getting her to team up with our newfound friends, Jenny and Manny — the latter being a producer for <a href="https://www.atv.at/tv/amore-unter-palmen">renowned Austrian TV shows</a>. Despite my enthusiasm, Nat remains modestly hesitant about embracing her newfound calling.</p>

<p>For me, that night wrapped up perfectly as I found myself and Christian stepping aside onto a terrace, away from the crowd. There, against the backdrop of a starlit sky, we shared a drink and delved into one of those rare, meandering conversations that only best friends can have — spanning everything and nothing all at once. It was one of those moments that encapsulate the essence of friendship, set against the vibrant tapestry of a night to remember.</p>

<h2 id="the-safari-and-beyond-a-tease-of-adventures-unfolded">The Safari and Beyond: A Tease of Adventures Unfolded</h2>

<p>As the wedding part of our Kenyan journey concluded, we were left with memories to last a lifetime and stories to fill countless evenings. Yet, there’s more to tell — safaris that brought us face-to-face with the wild heart of Africa, a secluded island that offered a slice of paradise, and a return to Dubai for a day of exploration.</p>

<p>But that is for another time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="africa" /><category term="kenya" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="african" /><category term="indian" /><category term="wedding" /><category term="dubai" /><category term="giraffes" /><category term="kenya" /><category term="safari" /><category term="sightseeing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us on a whirlwind journey from Singapore to Kenya for a unique African Indian wedding. Dive into the adventures, the unexpected delights, and the moments that tested our patience in the most beautiful ways.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tailor Tales and Tuk-Tuks: A Spontaneous Weekend in Vietnam</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/vietnam/tailor-tales-and-tuk-tuks-a-spontaneous-weekend-in-vietnam" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tailor Tales and Tuk-Tuks: A Spontaneous Weekend in Vietnam" /><published>2023-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/vietnam/tailor-tales-and-tuk-tuks-a-spontaneous-weekend-in-vietnam</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/vietnam/tailor-tales-and-tuk-tuks-a-spontaneous-weekend-in-vietnam"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-spontaneous-trip-to-vietnam">A Spontaneous Trip to Vietnam</h2>

<p>Singapore’s sunny shores, where flip-flops and shorts reign supreme, make for a laid-back wardrobe. But an invitation to my friend Hatim’s traditional Indian wedding in Africa, spanning five days with a different dress code for each, called for a wardrobe overhaul. Shorts and flip-flops wouldn’t cut it for an event brimming with culture and style. So, where does one turn for such a sartorial challenge? Vietnam, of course, specifically Hoi An – the tailoring capital.</p>

<h2 id="discovering-hoi-ans-tailoring-magic">Discovering Hoi An’s Tailoring Magic</h2>

<p>Our journey began with a swift and pleasant flight from Changi Airport to Da Nang. Hoi An awaited us, an hour’s drive from Da Nang. Here, nestled in the heart of Vietnam, is where tailoring artistry comes alive. Bong Tailors, a recommendation from my gym trainer and friend Bryan, did not disappoint. The excitement of getting custom-made clothing was palpable, a rare treat I’d only experienced once before, for a friend’s wedding in Beijing.</p>

<p>At Bong Tailors, we were greeted by the infectious enthusiasm of two Vietnamese ladies, ready to embark on our sartorial adventure. From the classic brown wool suit to the more outlandish blue silk number with golden dragon embroidery, the options seemed endless. And then, the pièce de résistance – matching silk pajamas for the dream team, my best friends Christian, Mera and Hatim, including their respective partners, a whimsical choice for the upcoming wedding.</p>

<h2 id="a-venture-into-vietnamese-craftsmanship">A Venture into Vietnamese Craftsmanship</h2>

<p>But it wasn’t just about the clothes. Across the street, a leather shop, run by the tailor’s sister, promised more treasures. Handmade shoes, a leather travel bag to match, and a belt – all crafted to perfection and ready overnight. Such efficiency and craftsmanship at surprisingly reasonable prices were a testament to Vietnam’s artisanal spirit.</p>

<h2 id="culinary-delights-and-local-sights">Culinary Delights and Local Sights</h2>

<p>Hoi An isn’t just about tailoring; it’s a city rich in flavors and sights. A Vietnamese medley for lunch introduced us to the local cuisine, from delectable pork dishes to fresh pomelo salad. Even in the old town, every turn brought new discoveries, from quaint restaurants to homemade ice cream sold straight from living rooms.</p>

<h2 id="experiencing-traditional-vietnam">Experiencing Traditional Vietnam</h2>

<p>Our adventure took a traditional turn with ox riding and circular boat tours – a mix of silly and fun, capturing the essence of local tourism. As we drove along, oxen dotted the roadside, leading us to an inevitable conclusion. Our driver nonchalantly pulled over beside a local with his ox, presenting it as our ride. The spontaneity was part of the charm. Climbing atop the ox, we couldn’t help but chuckle. It was an experience straight out of a travel comedy – riding ten meters down the road, then back again, all while a flurry of photos captured our every move. Nat took her turn, adding to the collection of memories with her own short jaunt. Together, we posed for pictures, embracing the touristy clichés with open arms.</p>

<h2 id="the-whimsical-ba-na-hills">The Whimsical Ba Na Hills</h2>

<p>Our final escapade was to Ba Na Hills, a place that defies description. A fake European city perched atop a hill, accessible by one of the world’s longest cable cars. Here, we found a blend of German, French, and Italian influences, complete with castles and a miniature Eiffel Tower. It was a surreal yet delightful experience, a playful nod to the wonders of imagination.</p>

<p>We weren’t sure if and how to take all this seriously – but it didn’t matter: We enjoyed it tremendously.</p>

<h2 id="back-to-singapore">Back to Singapore</h2>

<p>Our journey back to Singapore was bittersweet. The whirlwind of tailor-made suits, traditional experiences, and culinary delights left us enriched and eager for more. Vietnam, with its vibrant culture and skilled artisans, had given us memories to cherish and stories to tell.</p>

<p>In the end, this impromptu trip turned out to be more than just a shopping spree; it was a delightful juxtaposition of the silly and the serene; a journey into the heart of Vietnamese culture, craftsmanship, and hospitality. It reminded us that sometimes, the most memorable adventures are the ones that are least expected.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="asia" /><category term="vietnam" /><category term="vietnam" /><category term="hoi-an" /><category term="da-nang" /><category term="singapore" /><category term="tailor-made" /><category term="shopping" /><category term="silk-suits" /><category term="ox-riding" /><category term="boat-tours" /><category term="local-cuisine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ditching our usual Singaporean attire of shorts and flip-flops, we embarked on a spontaneous journey to Vietnam for a tailor-made adventure. From suits with dragon embroidery to traditional Vietnamese boats and ox rides, this trip was a whirlwind of unique experiences and delightful surprises.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greenland: An Arctic Adventure</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/europe/greenland/greenland-an-arctic-adventure" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greenland: An Arctic Adventure" /><published>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/europe/greenland/greenland-an-arctic-adventure</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/europe/greenland/greenland-an-arctic-adventure"><![CDATA[<p>Two years ago, a new camera entered my life, bringing along a path I hadn’t anticipated: free workshops on mastering photography. These weren’t just any classes; they were gateways to an adventure that would eventually lead me to the icy, rugged landscapes of Greenland. The first workshop was a humble beginning in a small room, but it was the second one, amidst the backdrop of Punggol’s sea and sunset in Singapore, where my journey truly began. There, I befriended Han and Germaine, photographers whose stunning Greenland captures on Instagram had long captivated me. Little did I know, a casual inquiry about joining them would catapult me into an Arctic adventure beyond my wildest dreams.</p>

<h2 id="preparing-for-the-arctic-chill">Preparing for the Arctic Chill</h2>

<p>Greenland, a land so distant from my tropical existence in Singapore, was an enigma. My only brush with the Arctic had been a trip to Iceland years back, which, while impressive, did not prepare me for the vast wilderness of Greenland. As the trip approached, our lively WhatsApp group buzzed with anticipation and a fair share of apprehension about the cold. Coming from the perpetual summer of Singapore, the thought of Greenlandic cold sent me on a last-minute shopping spree for insulated gear — a decision that proved both prudent and excessive as the adventure unfolded.</p>

<h2 id="a-rocky-start-to-the-adventure">A Rocky Start to the Adventure</h2>

<p>My journey began with a flight to Paris, a brief sojourn in Germany, and then a reunion with the group in Reykjavik — or more precisely, Keflavik, given the airport’s actual location. Our first hiccup came with a wind-cancelled flight, turning our anticipation into an extended stay in Iceland’s volatile weather. Yet, this delay offered us moments of camaraderie and unexpected delights, such as the excellent dinner at the Kef restaurant and the pragmatic warmth of the Keflavik microsuite, despite its sulfur-scented showers, a quirk of Iceland’s volcanic bounty.</p>

<h2 id="first-impressions-of-greenland">First Impressions of Greenland</h2>

<p>Finally, Greenland. The flight to Kulusuk was a preamble to the raw beauty and harsh realities of Arctic travel, with its small airports and weather-dependent schedules. Our intended helicopter ride to our final destination was thwarted by the weather, leaving us stranded yet again. However, even in these moments of delay, Greenland revealed its charm. The rustic hotel in Kulusuk, adorned with polar bear fur, served as a gateway to our first photographic expedition under the Arctic sky, painting colorful houses against a backdrop of ice and stone.</p>

<h2 id="the-majesty-of-ice-and-northern-lights">The Majesty of Ice and Northern Lights</h2>

<p>My preparedness for the trip, armed with a high-end camera and enthusiasm, met its match in the seasoned photographers of our group, who taught me the value of dual camera bodies in the cold. The kindness of Han, lending me a spare body, and the innovative solutions we found, like a boat ride to Amsilak in lieu of the helicopter, underscored the adventure’s spirit. I witnessed icebergs for the first time and the serene beauty of Amasilak’s landscape was transformative.</p>

<p>During the day, Greenland’s warmth is surprisingly mild, offering a pleasant break from the cold you’d expect. But as night falls, the scene shifts dramatically to something almost surreal—the Northern Lights or Aurora Borealis. This stunning display, a result of solar particles clashing with Earth’s magnetic atmosphere, splashes the sky with vibrant greens and, occasionally, pinks and violets.</p>

<p>Our group, equipped with cameras and bundled up against the cold, dedicated many hours under the stars to this captivating phenomenon. Witnessing the Northern Lights is an incredibly deep experience, far surpassing the beauty we managed to capture in photos. It’s like being part of a universal dance, with the lights weaving patterns that ignite a mix of wonder and a profound sense of connection.</p>

<p>The challenge of photographing the Northern Lights turned into our nightly endeavor, a test of our endurance against the biting cold. Despite all our preparations, the Arctic’s icy grip was a constant reminder of the harsh yet stunning environment surrounding us. However, enduring the cold was a small sacrifice for the awe-inspiring sight of the lights, which never repeated a pattern, ensuring each night’s display was unique.</p>

<p>But the Northern Lights are more than just a visual treat; they’re a link to ancient stories and legends of the Arctic’s indigenous cultures. These lights have sparked tales of deities, spirits, and the afterlife, shared by those who’ve lived under their glow for generations. In the quiet, expansive icy wilderness of Greenland, the lights seem to narrate these age-old tales, adding a profound layer to our experience.</p>

<p>Our evenings spent in pursuit of the Northern Lights were undoubtedly the pinnacle of our journey to Greenland, reminding us of the world’s extraordinary beauty and mystery. This fleeting and elusive experience left an indelible mark, ensuring our memories of the lights remain as vivid and lively as the spectacle itself.</p>

<h2 id="cultural-immersions-and-culinary-adventures">Cultural Immersions and Culinary Adventures</h2>

<p>Every day in Greenland was an adventure, far richer and more personal than I could have ever anticipated. From the moment we stepped onto its vast, untouched wilderness, it was clear that this was a land that defied the ordinary. One of the experiences was tasting whale blubber, a traditional dish that, while challenging for our palates, offered a tangible connection to the Inuit way of life. Similarly, the Tupilak carvings, intricate and laden with myth, spoke of a world where the spiritual and the earthly intertwine seamlessly.</p>

<p>Amidst this, the clear waters, massive icebergs, and the stark absence of trees painted a landscape so surreal it often felt like stepping into another dimension—one that photography and words struggled to capture fully. This sentiment was echoed in my interactions with Lukas Jahn, a fellow traveler whose passion for capturing Greenland’s essence on his YouTube channel inspired me. His dedication to portraying the raw beauty and the harsh realities of this land added depth to my own experience.</p>

<p>Both, a spoken and much more raw, less AI-polished version of my experiences in Greenland as well as links to Lukas you can find at my podcast <a href="https://www.sleepless.sg/4">Sleepless in Singapore</a>.</p>

<h2 id="reflecting-on-a-journey-unforgettable">Reflecting on a Journey Unforgettable</h2>

<p>Greenland was a journey of contrasts — of unexpected warmth amid the cold, of timeless landscapes and fleeting moments captured under the Northern Lights, of the solitude of remote huts against the backdrop of communal laughter. It was a reminder of the planet’s fragility, witnessed in the receding glaciers, and of humanity’s resilience, seen in the hunters’ respect for their environment. As we departed Greenland, the memories of icebergs, Northern Lights, and a world untouched by time lingered, reminding us of the adventure’s lasting impact on our hearts and minds.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><category term="greenland" /><category term="greenland" /><category term="photography" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="northern-lights" /><category term="icebergs" /><category term="wildlife" /><category term="arctic-culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Under the vast Arctic sky, our group of photographers from Singapore awaited the Northern Lights, a natural marvel that connected us to ancient Arctic legends. Amidst the surreal landscapes of Greenland, this ethereal display was more than a visual spectacle; it was a profound experience of connection and awe.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bangkok: Spontaneous Escapes and Culinary Adventures</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/thailand/bangkok-spontaneous-escapes-and-culinary-adventures" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bangkok: Spontaneous Escapes and Culinary Adventures" /><published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/thailand/bangkok-spontaneous-escapes-and-culinary-adventures</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/thailand/bangkok-spontaneous-escapes-and-culinary-adventures"><![CDATA[<p>Bangkok, a city synonymous with vivacious energy and vibrant streets, has a special place in my heart. Nestled among my top favorite cities, it stands distinct with its unique flavors and pulsating life. This tale is about my latest escapade to this fascinating city, a spontaneous getaway that turned into a feast for the senses.</p>

<h2 id="an-unplanned-journey">An Unplanned Journey</h2>

<p>It began as a spur-of-the-moment decision. After a sudden opening in our schedules, my fiancé Nat and I found ourselves yearning for a quick escape. Thanks to some accrued Singapore Airlines miles and an enticing offer from the Shangri-La Bangkok, our plan was swiftly set in motion. We departed from Changi Airport – an aviation marvel I can never stop praising – and soon landed in Bangkok’s bustling Suvarnabhumi Airport.</p>

<h2 id="first-impressions-and-river-encounters">First Impressions and River Encounters</h2>

<p>The Bangkok Shangri-La greeted us with its splendid river views, offering a panorama that captured the essence of the city’s dynamic spirit. Our room, blessed with protruded windows, provided a nearly 180-degree view over the Chao Phraya River, setting the stage for our adventure.</p>

<p>Eager to explore, we strolled the streets and stumbled upon the charming Bang Ruk Bazaar. Here’s a little secret for fellow travelers: opt for the local river boats. They’re an affordable way to soak in the same experiences as the tourist-laden alternatives, minus the typical commentary. This simple choice led us to a delightful encounter with an Indian couple, a testament to the unexpected connections travel often brings. In a twist of serendipity, Nat and this couple realized they shared a mutual acquaintance. The common thread, as my memory serves, was their university days where paths had crossed in the corridors of academia. Or it could have been entirely different, as Nat says, but that’s what my mind wants to remember.</p>

<h2 id="culinary-wonders">Culinary Wonders</h2>

<p>Bangkok’s culinary scene is an illustrious mosaic of flavors, but the pinnacle of our gastronomic adventure was at Gaggan, the brainchild of the culinary maestro, Gaggan Anand. This restaurant, a beacon of progressive Indian cuisine, has redefined dining with its innovative approach. Securing a reservation felt like aligning with the stars – a casual Instagram scroll unveiled a rare opportunity, and we seized it.</p>

<p>As we stepped into Gaggan, we were welcomed into a world where traditional Indian flavors married avant-garde gastronomy. Each course of the 18-course menu was a masterpiece, carefully choreographed to tell a story, to evoke emotion, and to surprise the palate. The setting was intimate, creating a personal narrative between the chef and us, the diners.</p>

<p>One of the standout moments was the explosive candied green leaf with yoghurt ball, a delicate yet bold start to the culinary symphony. As it melted in our mouths, it released bursts of flavors, setting the stage for the culinary journey ahead. The chocolate cone was a playful indulgence, inviting us to engage in the joy of eating with our hands, reminiscent of childhood innocence.</p>

<p>A dish resembling a mini garden, complete with ‘soil’ that was actually dehydrated mushrooms and edible flowers, was both a visual and a taste delight. There was a course where a perfectly grilled piece of fish was served on a miniature charcoal grill, still smoking and sizzling as it arrived at our table, its aroma enticing our senses even before we took the first bite.</p>

<p>A particular favorite was a dish inspired by the streets of Kolkata - a reimagination of the classic puchka. The playfulness in choosing the sequence of flavors added an interactive element that was both fun and delicious.</p>

<p>As our dining experience at Gaggan concluded, we were left with a profound appreciation for the creativity and passion that Gaggan Anand infuses into his cuisine. It was not just a meal; it was an artistic and sensory journey that redefined our understanding of Indian cuisine and set a new benchmark for culinary excellence.</p>

<h2 id="exploring-the-heart-of-bangkok">Exploring the Heart of Bangkok</h2>

<p>Our time in Bangkok was not just about indulging in food. (Although, if that was my choice and my choice only, it certainly would be.) We ventured into the city’s heart, visiting iconic landmarks like Wat Arun and the majestic Reclining Buddha. The contrast between the serene beauty of these ancient sites and the city’s modern hustle was striking.</p>

<p>Kaosan Road, a rite of passage for many Bangkok visitors, presented a lively yet somewhat overwhelming experience. We opted for a more laid-back evening at the Ratchada Train Market, a vibrant tapestry of sights, sounds, and smells that encapsulates the spirit of Bangkok.</p>

<p>The Ratchada Train Market, also known as Talad Rot Fai Ratchada, is a nocturnal wonderland that offers an immersive glimpse into local life. This open-air bazaar, set against a backdrop of colorful tents and neon lights, is a feast for the senses. As we meandered through the bustling aisles, the air was rich with the aroma of sizzling street food, the chatter of enthusiastic vendors, and the laughter of families and friends gathering for their evening meal.</p>

<p>What sets the Ratchada Train Market apart is its eclectic mix of offerings. From vintage clothing and quirky souvenirs to handmade crafts, it’s a treasure trove for shoppers looking for unique finds. But the real star here is undoubtedly the food. The market is a haven for food lovers, with stalls serving up everything from traditional Thai dishes to fusion cuisine and tantalizing desserts.</p>

<p>We indulged in spicy tofu bowls that tingled our taste buds with their bold flavors, and sampled what was touted as one of the best Pad Thai in the city - a claim that lived up to our expectations. The textures and tastes of each dish were a testament to the culinary prowess of the local chefs.</p>

<p>Perhaps the most memorable moment was standing before a stall selling an array of fried insects, a delicacy in Thai cuisine. The sight of crunchy crickets and other exotic snacks was both intriguing and intimidating. While we contemplated trying them, an Aussie gentleman, a seasoned connoisseur of these crunchy treats, heartily enjoyed them like everyday snacks.</p>

<h2 id="final-impressions">Final Impressions</h2>

<p>As our trip neared its end, we indulged in one last culinary escapade at the food court of ICONSIAM. In this foodie’s paradise, we savored delicate dumplings, each a perfect parcel of flavor, and indulged in multicolored mango sticky rice, a dish that was as much a feast for the eyes as it was for the palate. The sticky rice, vibrant in hues of natural coloring, paired with the sweet, ripe mango and creamy coconut milk, created a symphony of flavors that perfectly encapsulated the essence of Thai dessert mastery.</p>

<p>After our meal, we stumbled upon a hidden gem – a rooftop terrace next to a Starbucks at ICONSIAM. This serene oasis, high above the hustle and bustle of the city, offered panoramic views that took our breath away. The terrace, a perfect blend of urban sophistication and tranquility, provided a sweeping vista of the Chao Phraya River and the sprawling city skyline. As we sipped our coffees, the view of the iconic landmarks, juxtaposed against the modern skyscrapers, was a reminder of the city’s dynamic character.</p>

<p>Bangkok, with its endless surprises and vibrant spirit, never fails to enchant. From spontaneous trips to culinary expeditions, each visit adds a new chapter to my Bangkok tales, leaving me longing for the next journey to this extraordinary city.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="asia" /><category term="thailand" /><category term="bangkok" /><category term="travel-adventures" /><category term="culinary-experiences" /><category term="spontaneous-trips" /><category term="local-tips" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bangkok, a city synonymous with vivacious energy and vibrant streets, has a special place in my heart. Nestled among my top favorite cities, it stands distinct with its unique flavors and pulsating life. This tale is about my latest escapade to this fascinating city, a spontaneous getaway that turned into a feast for the senses.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Peaks to Peace: A Journey Through Laos</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/laos/from-peaks-to-peace-a-journey-through-laos" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Peaks to Peace: A Journey Through Laos" /><published>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/laos/from-peaks-to-peace-a-journey-through-laos</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/laos/from-peaks-to-peace-a-journey-through-laos"><![CDATA[<h2 id="an-unconventional-border-crossing">An Unconventional Border Crossing</h2>

<p>Leaving the familiar <a href="/travel/asia/thailand/scooters-and-surprises-chiang-mai-to-chiang-rai-and-beyond">hustle of Thailand</a> behind was straightforward enough, but the real adventure began as soon as we approached the border. There’s something about crossing a border by land that injects an extra thrill into travel. This wasn’t just any crossing; it involved a curious wait on the Thai side by the Friendship Bridge No. 5, a limbo of anticipation. We sat, waited, and watched as people gathered, a small crowd forming slowly until, after two hours, there were enough of us to justify sending a bus. The catch? You couldn’t just stroll across the bridge. Instead, we were herded onto a bus that chugged across the river, delivering us to the Laotian side with a bureaucratic welcome.</p>

<p>Arriving in Laos introduced us to the next chapter of this comedic border saga. Visa on arrival should be simple, right? Except, in our infinite wisdom, we had overlooked one small detail—passport photos. Standing there, at the mercy of the immigration officer, we learned that a lack of preparation could be easily solved with a little cash. With a grin, the officer directed us to his high-tech solution: a webcam photo session. It was another unexpected tourist tax, but honestly, the simplicity of it was hilarious in its own right.</p>

<h2 id="huay-xai-a-night-to-remember">Huay Xai: A Night to Remember</h2>

<p>Once officially admitted into Laos, our first stop was Huay Xai. The town itself was unassuming, a quiet pause before the next leg of our journey. We stayed at The Little Hostel, a place that lived up to its name with basic amenities and a charm only a $10-a-night lodging can offer. The owner was a delight, making our short stay there feel like a night at a friend’s house. There wasn’t much to do, but we ventured out, exploring a nearby hill with remnants of what seemed like a military outpost. Its age and purpose were as ambiguous as our path up the hill, but it added an element of mystery to our brief exploration.</p>

<p>Our stay in Huay Xai was fleeting because the real draw of the area was yet to come—the Mekong River.</p>

<h2 id="a-journey-down-the-mekong">A Journey Down the Mekong</h2>

<p>The allure of the Mekong had called to us long before we arrived, and the experience did not disappoint. We opted for the more expensive boat, a decision that paid off with comfort and panoramic views that seemed straight out of a travel magazine. With only ten of us on board, the spacious boat felt like our private mobile haven. We lounged, chatted, and absorbed the ever-changing landscapes that unfolded along the riverbanks.</p>

<p>The “floating lunch” served aboard was a culinary highlight, turning simple meals into memorable feasts with the backdrop of the Mekong’s serene waters. Despite the lack of luxury, the journey was profoundly relaxing, offering a much-needed respite from the usual travel frenzy.</p>

<p>Our adventure was punctuated by stops at remote Laotian villages, where the simplicity of life was stark and the authenticity palpable. One such stop introduced us to local traditions and crafts, including a potent homemade alcohol, intriguingly stored in bottles with ginseng and baby cobra snakes.</p>

<h2 id="unexpected-turns-in-pak-beng">Unexpected Turns in Pak Beng</h2>

<p>The quaint town of Pak Beng was our resting point for the night, a place marked by its basic, albeit slightly adventurous, accommodations. Our dinner was forgettable, but the evening was saved by a visit to the Happy Bar, a hotspot for backpackers craving a taste of home—or at least a poorly mixed cocktail.</p>

<p>The night took a turn for the wetter as one of our rooms decided to embody the river itself, flooding during a nighttime downpour. With luggage perched safely on beds, we waded through our impromptu indoor pool.</p>

<h2 id="back-to-the-boat">Back to the Boat</h2>

<p>The next morning brought more comedy. Our host attempted to shuttle us back to the boat, cycling through vehicles with the hopefulness of a gambler. Cars failed to start, scooters refused to cooperate, and even a multi-passenger scooter loaded with us and a few barnyard animals couldn’t manage the trek. Eventually, we embraced the inevitable and walked to the boat, a fitting start to another day of languid river travel.</p>

<h2 id="reflections-on-the-river">Reflections on the River</h2>

<p>Our journey was as peaceful as the first, with more floating meals and languid hours spent watching the landscapes shift. The Mekong had offered us a retreat from the world, a stretch of time where the only pressing matters were the passing scenery and the next meal.</p>

<h2 id="a-rocky-start-in-luang-prabang">A Rocky Start in Luang Prabang</h2>

<p>Our arrival in Luang Prabang was less than ideal but memorable. Initially, we checked into a hotel that challenged our very definition of hospitality. The first room assigned to us was overwhelmingly smelly. In search of relief, we were moved to another room only to find the shower non-operational. The hotel’s “ingenious” solution was for us to sleep in the non-smelly room and use the smelly room just for showers, minimizing our exposure to the mysterious odors. This arrangement was as bizarre as it sounds, and needless to say, we didn’t stick around.</p>

<p>After one uncomfortable night, we upgraded to the Pullman Luang Prabang. This change was like stepping into a different world—a world where the air was fresh, the beds inviting, and the pool a cool sanctuary from the heat. Here, everything was as it should be: clean, comfortable, and utterly relaxing. We captured countless photos against the picturesque backdrop.</p>

<p>In the evening, we ventured to the local market for dinner. The food, while not memorable, was engulfed in the vibrant hustle of market life, offering a slice of local culture amid our hotel dramas.</p>

<h2 id="the-hike-that-nearly-wasnt">The Hike That Nearly Wasn’t</h2>

<p>Eager to share a piece of my past adventures, I promised Hatim a spectacular hike to the famous waterfalls of Luang Prabang. Memories of serene pools and lush landscapes fueled our ascent. However, reality quickly dampened our spirits. The waterfalls, once a vibrant cascade of clear pools, were now a disappointing trickle amid debris-strewn waters. The season, or perhaps just the passage of time, had not been kind to this once idyllic spot. Poor Hatim, gasping for breath and hope, found little reward at the summit. The descent was a quiet acknowledgment of expectations unmet—a hike more memorable for its anticipation than its payoff.</p>

<h2 id="a-serene-escape-to-vang-vieng">A Serene Escape to Vang Vieng</h2>

<p>Seeking a change of scenery and pace, we boarded a modern Chinese-built high-speed train to Vang Vieng. This journey was a smooth transition, nestled in the comfort of clean, efficient service that contrasted sharply with our earlier trials. Vang Vieng welcomed us with open arms and a tranquil vibe that was perfect for winding down.</p>

<p>Our days in Vang Vieng were spent largely at our hotel, a cozy retreat from the relentless heat and our travel fatigue. Here, I found space to catch up on work, blending the lines between vacation and vocation. Despite the subdued end to our travels in Laos, Vang Vieng offered a peaceful backdrop to reflect on the weeks of incredible experiences and occasional misadventures.</p>

<h2 id="final-notes-and-forward-flights">Final Notes and Forward Flights</h2>

<p>Our journey concluded with a brief stop in Vientiane before catching our flights home—Hatim extended his adventure with a stay in Singapore, while I returned to familiar surroundings. Our travels through Laos left us with a mixed bag of stories, from the comedic to the serene, each underscored by the unpredictable nature of travel.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="asia" /><category term="laos" /><category term="border-crossing" /><category term="freedom-bridge" /><category term="huay-xai" /><category term="laos" /><category term="mekong-river" /><category term="thailand" /><category term="travel-adventures" /><category term="visa" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Navigating the quirky customs at the Thailand-Laos border, our journey took a comedic turn, from webcam visa photos to a torrentially flooded room in Pak Beng. Our adventure was dotted with unexpected camaraderie and the picturesque serenity of the Mekong River.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Scooters and Surprises: Chiang Mai to Chiang Rai and Beyond</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/thailand/scooters-and-surprises-chiang-mai-to-chiang-rai-and-beyond" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scooters and Surprises: Chiang Mai to Chiang Rai and Beyond" /><published>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/thailand/scooters-and-surprises-chiang-mai-to-chiang-rai-and-beyond</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/thailand/scooters-and-surprises-chiang-mai-to-chiang-rai-and-beyond"><![CDATA[<h2 id="unplanned-beginnings-and-open-waters">Unplanned Beginnings and Open Waters</h2>

<p>After a <a href="/travel/asia/malaysia/malaysias-road-less-traveled-a-tale-of-friendship-and-light-packing">calm morning in Georgetown</a>, the day unfolded with a spontaneous kind of chaos. It began at a border not yet open; an early morning wait, the sun rising slow and lazy as if it too struggled with the day’s beginnings. The border officers arrived, a flicker of life in sleepy offices, and soon after, we were on a train rumbling its way towards Surat Thani. This southern city, a gateway to the islands, buzzed with the kind of energy only pivotal crossroads possess.</p>

<p>We arrived without plans, without tickets—our sights set loosely on Koh Tao. But as fate would have it, the boat to Koh Tao had already sailed. Flexibility being the unsung hero of travel, we adapted quickly. The ticket master, with a grin revealing the routine nature of such traveler woes, directed us to the next available boat—a slow boat to Koh Phangan.</p>

<p>These boats, relics of a bygone era, were a spectacle in themselves. Over a century old by their looks, they served as floating microcosms of Thai life. The lower deck, a chaos of cargo—from pineapples to motorbikes—spoke of the island’s needs. The top deck, however, was reserved for passengers and makeshift beds. Fifty mattresses lined each side, transforming the space into a communal sleeping area where personal bubbles overlapped with ease.</p>

<p>The slow boat experience was a cultural tapestry—old men sneaking smokes by the windows, families sharing homemade meals, and travelers exchanging stories. Among the cacophony, a chance encounter with a loquacious local made for a memorable, if somewhat bewildering, conversation about distant lands. Despite a few awkward exchanges, the spirit of shared journey pervaded, drawing us all into the late hours until sleep claimed the weary and excited alike.</p>

<h2 id="koh-phangan-to-koh-tao-diving-into-serenity">Koh Phangan to Koh Tao: Diving into Serenity</h2>

<p>Morning light brought Koh Phangan into view, a brief stop before we resumed our journey to Koh Tao. Transitioning boats, we soon arrived at the Jamahkiri Resort, a place of rustic charm perched atop the rocky coastline. The villas, with their stunning sea views, offered a serene respite from our boat adventure’s cramped quarters.</p>

<p>Koh Tao unfolded in hues of blue and green—a diver’s paradise. While Hatim opted out, I plunged into the underwater world. The dives were blissful escapes into the marine abyss, filled with vibrant corals and bustling marine life. On the surface, evenings were spent at local haunts, sharing meals and tales with travelers and expats alike.</p>

<h2 id="a-cultural-whirlwind-from-chumphon-to-bangkok">A Cultural Whirlwind: From Chumphon to Bangkok</h2>

<p>Our departure from Koh Tao on yet another boat brought unexpected luxury. Stumbling upon the ‘super VIP’ section of the ferry, we found comfort in plush seats and tranquility—a stark contrast to our earlier sea voyages. The journey to Chumphon was smooth, and with no one to collect the extra fee for our accidental upgrade, it felt like a small victory.</p>

<p>Chumphon was a pause in our journey, a chance to breathe before the train ride to Bangkok. The town offered little in the way of tourist attractions, which suited us fine. We indulged in local delights, from street food to soothing massages, filling the hours before our train’s departure. The train itself was a step back in time, its carriages echoing the golden age of rail travel. Our seats, rigid and upright, weren’t made for sleep, but the experience was enriched by the characters we met—like the elderly Thai lady who, despite the language barrier, shared selfies and smiles, making any discomfort easily forgotten.</p>

<h2 id="bangkok-a-city-of-endless-discovery">Bangkok: A City of Endless Discovery</h2>

<p>Bangkok welcomed us with its characteristic fervor. Armed with only our light backpacks, we explored the city’s multifaceted personality. From the bustling floating markets to the high-end malls of Siam Bangkok, the city was a tapestry of the traditional and the modern. We navigated its canals, indulged in street food, and even found respite in a rooftop Starbucks, offering a panoramic view of the sprawling metropolis.</p>

<p>Our day concluded on a high note with a delightful discovery—a burger place in an old building, its food a pleasant surprise amidst the urban hustle. As we boarded our train to Chiang Mai, our spirits were high, filled with stories and friendships forged along the way.</p>

<h2 id="a-scooter-saga-in-chiang-mai">A Scooter Saga in Chiang Mai</h2>

<p>Our stay in Chiang Mai kicked off at the beautiful Melia Hotel, a spot that combined luxury with the lively spirit of the city. Chiang Mai always brims with energy and possibility, and this time was no different. Eager to dive into the local scene, we rented scooters, an essential for navigating the bustling streets and alleys. With our licenses in hand, we felt prepared—only to face our first hurdle just around the corner from the rental place.</p>

<p>A routine police checkpoint became our unexpected welcome party. Discussions about the validity of our international licenses ensued. While tensions could have escalated, the mood shifted when we opted for cooperation over confrontation. For a mere $20, we not only smoothed over the situation but also found ourselves escorted to the police station, where we were issued temporary Thai driving permits amidst laughs and selfies with the officers and fellow tourists.</p>

<h2 id="ascending-to-temples-and-tastes">Ascending to Temples and Tastes</h2>

<p>With our newly minted permissions, we ventured toward the mountains, scooters humming beneath us. The roads wound their way up, offering scenic vistas and the thrill of open air. Our destination was a revered temple, nestled high in the hills. Here, amidst the sacred chants and the fragrance of incense, we received blessings.</p>

<p>The return to Melia was less tranquil, thanks to a stringent dress code at the hotel bar. My choice of footwear, upscale flip-flops, clashed with the hotel’s policy, nearly leading to a standoff between Hatim and the staff. Resolving to keep the peace, we decided against spending our evening there, opting instead for the vibrant local scene, which did not disappoint.</p>

<h2 id="delights-and-dietary-diversions">Delights and Dietary Diversions</h2>

<p>The next day at Melia, we balanced relaxation with activity, hitting the gym and lounging by the pool. A peculiar encounter with the hotel’s dining policy over something as simple as french fries highlighted the sometimes-comical rigidity of rules. The inability to order fries poolside due to a “broken fryer” became an amusing anecdote of our trip, though the fresh fruit platters offered a delightful, if unintentional, healthier alternative.</p>

<p>Dinner brought us to a hidden gem in the Niman area, known for its eclectic eateries. The restaurant, a bustling spot whose name escaped me, offered a feast for the senses. Deep fried eggs topped with crispy onions and chilies, alongside roti prata and curry, showcased the depth of Northern Thai cuisine. Our meal was complemented by an array of vegetarian dishes, each bursting with flavor and freshness.</p>

<h2 id="journeying-to-chiang-rai-and-beyond">Journeying to Chiang Rai and Beyond</h2>

<p>Our travels took us next to Chiang Rai, where a car ride replaced our scooters. The drive was punctuated by stops at local markets, where onsen eggs provided a quick, savory snack. Our visit to the breathtaking white church in Pao Don Chai revealed an architectural marvel, its intricate designs a testament to the craftsman’s artistry—a stark.</p>

<p>Though our time in Chiang Rai was brief, it served as a gateway to the next chapter of our journey—<a href="/travel/asia/laos/from-peaks-to-peace-a-journey-through-laos">crossing into Laos</a>. The border crossing was a blend of chaos and camaraderie, with fellow travelers sharing tips and tales of their own adventures. As we stepped onto Laotian soil, the promise of new discoveries and cultural encounters beckoned, setting the stage for the next leg of our adventure.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="asia" /><category term="thailand" /><category term="thailand" /><category term="boats" /><category term="koh-tao" /><category term="diving" /><category term="culture" /><category term="local-tips" /><category term="chiang-mai" /><category term="chiang-rai" /><category term="laos" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="culture" /><category term="scooters" /><category term="temples" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From unplanned boat rides across sparkling Thai waters to the haphazard delights of Bangkok's bustling streets, our journey through Thailand was nothing short of an adventure. Strangers, night boats, and the vibrant life at sea set the stage for an unforgettable voyage.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Malaysia’s Road Less Traveled: A Tale of Friendship and Light Packing</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/malaysia/malaysias-road-less-traveled-a-tale-of-friendship-and-light-packing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Malaysia’s Road Less Traveled: A Tale of Friendship and Light Packing" /><published>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/malaysia/malaysias-road-less-traveled-a-tale-of-friendship-and-light-packing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/asia/malaysia/malaysias-road-less-traveled-a-tale-of-friendship-and-light-packing"><![CDATA[<p>Travel has always been about the people as much as the places. Reconnecting with my old friend Hatim, who I last met half a year before in South Africa, for a road trip across Malaysia was a reminder of that. There’s something deeply satisfying about plotting points on a map and tracing the route with someone who shares your thirst for discovery. This time around, I was especially eager—fresh off a luggage-laden expedition to Japan, the allure of traveling light promised a refreshing change of pace.</p>

<h2 id="the-art-of-packing-light">The Art of Packing Light</h2>

<p>Hatim and I agreed early on: we’d travel with the bare minimum. After the cumbersome experience of hauling heavy bags through Japan’s bustling streets, the appeal of minimalism was undeniable. So, with nothing but a small leather bike messenger backpack slung over my shoulders, I set off. This wasn’t just any backpack; it was my entire suitcase for the trip, weighing less than 5 kg. Packed within were a few merino wool t-shirts—my go-to for their comfort and durability—a couple of shorts, and essential toiletries neatly tucked into a transparent pouch that complied with airline regulations. I had embraced the art of packing light, and it felt liberating.</p>

<p>Shoes can make or break a travel experience, especially when you choose to forgo the usual footwear for something as simple as flip-flops. On this trip, I opted for a pair of high-quality leather flip-flops, vastly overpriced but equally durable, having survived numerous trips and still holding up strong. They were a testament to the idea that sometimes, the right kind of simple can be just perfect.</p>

<h2 id="malacca-a-blend-of-old-and-new">Malacca: A Blend of Old and New</h2>

<p>Our first stop was Malacca, a city whose historical patina and vibrant night markets create a tapestry of cultural fusion. Our explorations began almost immediately after we arrived. We dined at the Curly Tail, enjoying steaks and sharing a foie gras starter, a nod to the city’s eclectic culinary scene. The pandan cheesecake we tried was an adventure in itself—strange yet familiar, much like the city.</p>

<p>After dinner, we wandered the streets, soaking in the ambiance of The Old Merchant, a bar that perfectly encapsulated the blend of Asian and Western influences with its live music and cozy setting. Malacca’s charm lies in its ability to be profoundly historical yet vibrantly modern at the same time. As we strolled along the river and through the bustling night market, the city’s energy was palpable, a vibrant pulse that fueled our wanderlust.</p>

<h2 id="cameron-highlands-natures-embrace">Cameron Highlands: Nature’s Embrace</h2>

<p>Leaving the urban charm of Malacca behind, our journey took us to the serene greenery of Cameron Highlands. This segment of our trip was highlighted by a visit to a vast strawberry farm, where the air was as fresh as the strawberries we picked. Later, we indulged in a local culinary adventure—Mukata, a Thai BBQ hot pot that tantalized our taste buds with its flavorsome broth enriched by the dripping fats from the grilled meat.</p>

<p>Our stay in a quaint Airbnb, reminiscent of a stone villa, provided a perfect end to our days spent exploring the highlands. The mornings were greeted with breathtaking views of the sunrise over tea plantations, a scene so stunning that no camera could truly capture its essence. This part of Malaysia, with its rolling hills and lush landscapes, was a stark contrast to the historical urbanity of Malacca and stood as a testament to the country’s diverse beauty.</p>

<h2 id="a-stolen-gopro-and-a-new-perspective">A stolen GoPro and a New Perspective</h2>

<p>The incident with the stolen GoPro at the cafe was a jarring interruption to our otherwise serene experience in the Cameron Highlands. As we retraced our steps to the cafe, the sinking feeling of loss was palpable—the GoPro wasn’t just a camera; it held memories of our travels, moments that were irreplaceable. When we reached the cafe, a quick scan of the area confirmed our fears: the camera was nowhere in sight. We asked around, hoping for a glimmer of honesty, but it seemed all was lost. That is, until I remembered the GoPro’s remote functionality—a feature I had seldom used but now clung to as a last thread of hope.</p>

<p>Activating the remote beep through the app, we were met with silence at first. Then, a faint beeping echoed from a nearby table, specifically from a young tourist’s backpack. The moment was surreal as the beeping grew louder, drawing the attention of everyone around. The girl’s face turned a shade of red, a clear sign of guilt, as she reluctantly retrieved the camera from her bag. Her feeble excuses were doing little to mask the embarrassment of being caught. Despite the resolution, the incident left a bitter taste.</p>

<h2 id="georgetown">Georgetown</h2>

<p>Arriving in Georgetown under the steady drum of rainfall could have been a dampener, but for Hatim and me, it was merely a shift in our adventure’s backdrop. Georgetown, nestled on the northwest coast of Penang Island, is a gem that shines regardless of the weather. Its old town, brimming with charm and history, beckons with open arms, inviting you to explore its every nook.</p>

<h2 id="a-birthday-to-remember">A Birthday to Remember</h2>

<p>Our exploration of Georgetown began somewhat untraditionally—inside the playful walls of a fun museum. With the rain lashing outside, we found refuge among the oversized installations—it’s not every day you see soup bowls large enough to sit in or giant pasta you can pretend to cook. It was unexpected but ended up being a delightful diversion from the rain and an amusing prelude to a memorable evening.</p>

<p>It was my birthday, and the day brought with it an exceptional celebration. Hatim, together with Nat who joined us remotely, treated me to an exquisite Japanese omakase dinner at Wako Sushi. The restaurant, reserved just for us, provided an intimate setting that allowed us to enjoy the chef’s undivided attention. Each dish was not only a visual delight but an explosion of flavors, making the evening truly special. The thoughtful planning by Hatim and Nat turned the day into one I’d cherish forever.</p>

<h2 id="georgetowns-morning-and-a-journey-by-train">Georgetown’s Morning and a Journey by Train</h2>

<p>The following morning, we visited the Mugshot Café, a spot I remembered fondly from years past. It retained its charm and served a breakfast that perfectly set the tone for the day. Fueled and ready, we then navigated our way to the ferry, crossing over to the mainland to catch a train headed towards Malaysia’s northern border.</p>

<p>There’s something inherently liberating about train travel, especially in regions where time seems to slow down, and the modern world has lightly brushed against the old ways. The trains here are not about luxury; they’re about experience. As we settled into our standard class seats, the rhythmic clacking of the rails and the breeze from the open doors whispered stories of a bygone era. This ride wasn’t just a mode of transportation; it was a passage through the heart of Southeast Asia, wrapped in the simple pleasure of anticipation and the freedom of the open track.</p>

<h2 id="serendipity-and-seas-from-train-to-boat">Serendipity and Seas: From Train to Boat</h2>

<p>The journey continued as we approached the Thai border, a segment marked by a mix of waiting and wandering. Border crossings have their own rhythm and rituals, and ours was no exception, filled with small discoveries and interactions. Once across, our <a href="/travel/asia/thailand/scooters-and-surprises-chiang-mai-to-chiang-rai-and-beyond">next leg took us to Surat Thani</a>, a gateway to Thailand’s famed islands.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="asia" /><category term="malaysia" /><category term="malaysia" /><category term="friendship" /><category term="travel" /><category term="light-packing" /><category term="road-trip" /><category term="southeast-asia" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reuniting with my friend Hatim for a road trip across Malaysia, I embraced the joys of traveling light and uncovered the simplicity and freedom it brings to the adventurous soul. From Malacca’s historical streets to the lush greenery of Cameron Highlands, this journey was about reconnecting and rediscovering.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Road Trip: Exploring the Eastern U.S. with Markus</title><link href="https://www.locolust.com/travel/americas/usa/a-road-trip-exploring-the-eastern-u-s-with-markus" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Road Trip: Exploring the Eastern U.S. with Markus" /><published>2022-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.locolust.com/travel/americas/usa/a-road-trip-exploring-the-eastern-u-s-with-markus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.locolust.com/travel/americas/usa/a-road-trip-exploring-the-eastern-u-s-with-markus"><![CDATA[<p>After a short trip to Jakarta and Surabaya – stay tuned for more –, it was time to shift gears and embark on a new adventure – a road trip across the eastern United States with my good friend Markus. This journey promised a different kind of excitement, blending the thrill of exploration with the comfort of reconnecting with an old friend. Markus, who had been living in the U.S. for a couple of years, suggested the trip during one of our rare phone calls. It didn’t take long for us to decide that a road trip was the perfect way to explore the diverse landscapes and vibrant cities of the eastern U.S.</p>

<h2 id="the-longest-flight">The Longest Flight</h2>

<p>The adventure began with the longest regular flight in the world – Singapore to New York on <a href="https://mainlymiles.com/2022/01/12/singapore-airlines-goes-triple-daily-to-new-york-with-the-return-of-non-stop-newark-flights/">SQ24</a>. I was thrilled about this flight, not just because of its duration but also because the plane had no economy seats, only premium economy and business class. The journey was smooth, albeit slightly marred by an overzealous seat neighbor convinced my foot would accidentally open the plane door. Despite this minor annoyance, the flight was a unique experience, whisking me halfway around the world in just 18 hours and 40 minutes.</p>

<p>Landing in New York, I spent my first night at a modest Hilton in the heart of the city. The next morning, bagel in hand, I boarded a <a href="https://www.amtrak.com/stations/nyp.html">train to Philadelphia</a>. The train ride was surprisingly comfortable, and soon enough, I was reunited with Markus at the station. We wasted no time catching up on lost years and shared stories over a meal before heading to his place in <a href="https://visitkop.com">King of Prussia</a>.</p>

<h2 id="starting-the-road-trip">Starting the Road Trip</h2>

<p>The real journey began the following day. Our plan was to drive from Pennsylvania down to Louisiana and then loop back up along the eastern coast. The route would take us through a mix of bustling cities and serene landscapes, offering a perfect blend of urban excitement and natural beauty. Our first stop was <a href="https://www.mountvernon.org">Mount Vernon</a>, George Washington’s historic estate. The sprawling grounds and well-preserved mansion provided a fascinating glimpse into the life of the first U.S. president.</p>

<h2 id="a-taste-of-the-south">A Taste of the South</h2>

<p>From there, we headed south, making our way through Virginia and into North Carolina. The change in scenery was immediate and refreshing. Rolling hills and lush greenery replaced the urban landscape as we ventured deeper into the South. Our journey took us to Asheville, a charming city nestled in the Blue Ridge Mountains.</p>

<p>The second night on our trip, we found ourselves at a quaint little hotel that had all the charm of an old-school American motel. As we walked into the bar, we were greeted by the barkeeper who seemed genuinely excited to have travelers stopping by. The place had a rustic feel, with everything made from wood, deer heads mounted on the walls, and a selection of twenty different craft beers. It felt like a scene straight out of a classic American movie.</p>

<p>The atmosphere was relaxed, with country music playing softly in the background. A man wearing a hat with the US flag was chatting with the barkeeper, and the big TV on the wall was turned off, as if to emphasize the importance of good conversation over mindless entertainment. This was America at its best, a warm, welcoming place where stories were shared over a cold beer.</p>

<h2 id="the-thrill-of-the-blue-ridge-parkway">The Thrill of the Blue Ridge Parkway</h2>

<p>The next morning, we continued our journey along the <a href="https://www.blueridgeparkway.org">Blue Ridge Parkway</a>. This stretch of road is renowned for its stunning views and scenic overlooks, and it did not disappoint. We took our time, stopping frequently to take pictures and simply soak in the beauty of the landscape. Driving along the winding roads, with the mountains rising majestically around us, was an experience I won’t soon forget.</p>

<p>Our car, a classic American muscle car, added to the thrill of the drive. Unlike the sleek, agile sports cars of Europe, this beast had a weight and presence that you could feel in every turn. The deep, resonant growl of the engine echoed through the tunnels we passed, making the whole car vibrate. It was the perfect vehicle for this kind of road trip, embodying the spirit of American adventure.</p>

<p>One unplanned stop was <a href="https://www.ncparks.gov/state-parks/mount-mitchell-state-park">Mount Mitchell</a>. Standing at 6,684 feet, it’s the highest peak east of the Mississippi River. We hadn’t initially planned to visit, but the sight of the towering mountain was too tempting to resist. Driving almost all the way to the top, we were rewarded with panoramic views that were simply breathtaking. It was a short detour but one of the highlights of our trip.</p>

<h2 id="a-glimpse-into-cherokee-and-gatlinburg">A Glimpse into Cherokee and Gatlinburg</h2>

<p>After leaving Mount Mitchell, we made our way to Cherokee. This small town, with its rich Native American history, was a fascinating stop. We visited the Oconaluftee Visitor Center, which provided a great insight into the cultural heritage of the area. From there, we headed to Gatlinburg, Tennessee, a town that seemed to encapsulate the essence of Southern charm.</p>

<p>Gatlinburg was a delight. We stayed at a modest motel in Oneida, which, while not luxurious, was clean and comfortable. Our dinner at the <a href="https://greenbrierrestaurant.com">Greenbrier</a> was an experience in itself. The stone building, with a G emblazoned on top, offered a cozy, rustic atmosphere. We enjoyed a meal of grits with a generous dollop of butter, followed by steak with sauce béarnaise, asparagus, and glazed carrots. It was a feast that left us thoroughly satisfied.</p>

<h2 id="the-road-ahead">The Road Ahead</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/us/royal-inn-oneida.en-gb.html">Royal Inn in Oneida</a> may not have been the most luxurious place we’ve stayed. It was one of those motels you see in movies, with simple, no-frills rooms. After a long day of driving, Markus and I sat outside our rooms, enjoying a beer and a cigarette.</p>

<p>After waking up in this not-so-cozy motel, with an incessantly noisy AC by a noisy highway, we set our sights on the Mammoth Caves. With over 600 kilometers of underground passages, it’s the world’s most extensive cave system. Admittedly, we weren’t thrilled at first, but it was a must-see detour that took us a bit north into Kentucky before heading south to Nashville.</p>

<p>The visitor center at <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mammoth_Cave_National_Park">Mammoth Caves</a> was bustling, and parking was a bit of a challenge. After navigating through the crowds, we finally got to explore the caves. The accessible section was impressive but not quite as grand as the statistics had led us to imagine. Still, it was worth the visit, especially noting the measures taken to protect the bats, like the shoe-cleaning stations to prevent the spread of harmful microbes.</p>

<p>Onward we drove, making miles down to <a href="http://skidaddys.info">Ski Daddy’s</a> for lunch—a family-owned joint known for deep-fried American classics. We indulged in fries, fish, and mozzarella sticks. It was okay, not life-changing, but a decent slice of local flavor.</p>

<h2 id="nightlife-and-nostalgia-in-nashville">Nightlife and Nostalgia in Nashville</h2>

<p>Arriving in Nashville, we checked into a charming Airbnb in a quintessentially American house just outside the city center. Spacious garden, cozy terrace, and well-maintained interiors—it was a perfect base.</p>

<p>Nashville, often synonymous with country music, was a revelation. The city center was alive with energy. We stumbled upon a parade of sorts, only to be told it was just a regular Saturday night. People were partying on converted buses, dancing, and singing along to blasting music. We joined the crowd at <a href="http://www.honkytonkcentral.com">Honky Tonk Central</a>, a massive bar where live country music filled the air. The atmosphere was electric, with locals and visitors alike reveling in the lively nightlife.</p>

<p>We mingled with folks from all over, including a bunch from California who had flown in for the weekend. The camaraderie was palpable, and the night stretched into the wee hours. Back at our Airbnb, we crashed into a deep sleep, exhausted but exhilarated.</p>

<h2 id="memphis-echoes-of-elvis">Memphis: Echoes of Elvis</h2>

<p>The next morning, still buzzing from Nashville, we hit the road to Memphis. Breakfast via Uber Eats was a letdown—$26 for a sad avocado toast that was little more than a thin smear on cheap bread topped with Costco bagel mix. Not the gourmet start we hoped for, but it fueled us enough to continue our journey.</p>

<p>Driving into Memphis, the vibe shifted. We cruised by <a href="https://www.graceland.com">Graceland</a>, the legendary home of Elvis Presley, capturing a few snapshots of the opulent exterior and vintage airplanes. The museum itself we skipped—too touristy for our taste, but the outside spectacle was enough to appreciate Elvis’s legacy.</p>

<p>For a quirky dining experience, we hit a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sonic_Drive-In">Sonic Drive-In</a>. Unlike a typical drive-through, this was a drive-in where you park and order from your car. A server then brings your food directly to your vehicle. It felt nostalgic, like stepping into an old American movie scene. The food was typical fast food—nothing to write home about, but the experience was unique.</p>

<h2 id="sleeping-where-history-was-made">Sleeping where History was made</h2>

<p>That night we stayed in a unique Airbnb that doubled as a recording studio. The charm of this place was undeniable, with its retro decor and memorabilia from the golden age of music. Sleeping in a place with such a rich history was an experience in itself, and it set the tone for our exploration of Memphis.</p>

<p>Our evening stroll through downtown Memphis led us to The Waltz, a local hotspot, followed by a visit to the <a href="https://www.civilrightsmuseum.org">Lorraine Motel</a>. This motel is famous as the site where Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. was assassinated in 1968. The motel has been preserved to look as it did in the ’60s, complete with vintage cars parked out front. It was a poignant experience, reminding us of the significant historical events that took place here.</p>

<p>Hungry from our sightseeing, we headed to <a href="https://eatcbq.com">Central BBQ</a> for a quintessential Memphis meal. The BBQ in Memphis is legendary, and it did not disappoint. Markus had a feast of sausage, pork ribs, chicken, cornbread, and corn salad, while I indulged in pork ribs, brisket, pulled pork, and baked beans. The craft beer selection was excellent, rounding off a perfect evening.</p>

<h2 id="discovering-the-delta">Discovering the Delta</h2>

<p>The next day, we made our way to the <a href="https://stores.basspro.com/us/tn/memphis/1-bass-pro-dr.html">Bass Pro Shop Outdoor World</a> in Memphis. This isn’t just any store; it’s a massive pyramid-shaped building that is part amusement park, part outdoor retailer. You can find everything from baseball caps to yachts here.</p>

<p>From Memphis, we drove along the Mississippi River, witnessing the changing landscapes as we traveled south. The flatlands of Mississippi were a stark contrast to the mountainous regions we had passed earlier. The drive was a journey through history, with numerous signs and landmarks marking the sites of old plantations and Civil War battles.</p>

<p>One of our stops was the <a href="https://www.nps.gov/vick/index.htm">Vicksburg National Military Park</a>, a drive-through museum that offers a glimpse into the Civil War era. It’s fascinating how you can drive through this vast park, taking in the history from the comfort of your car. The sheer scale of the park was impressive, and it gave us a deeper appreciation for the history of the region.</p>

<h2 id="embracing-new-orleans">Embracing New Orleans</h2>

<p>Our journey culminated in New Orleans, where we stayed in one of the best Airbnbs of our trip. The house was enormous, with a giant kitchen and a living room that could easily fit four of mine back home. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_Quarter">French Quarter</a> location was perfect, allowing us to immerse ourselves in the vibrant culture of New Orleans.</p>

<p>We spent our days exploring the city and our nights indulging in the local cuisine. One day, we went on a swamp tour with <a href="https://ragincajunairboattours.com">Ragin Cajun Boat Tours</a>. These flat-bottomed boats, equipped with fans, skim across the shallow waters, allowing you to get up close to the wildlife. We saw alligators, birds, and other swamp creatures. At one point, my baseball cap flew off into the water, and our guide had to retrieve it, only for me to throw it away later because it smelled like swamp.</p>

<p>Continuing our Louisiana adventure, we dined at a traditional restaurant where Markus enjoyed a plate of oysters, and I tried alligator bites. They tasted surprisingly like chicken, albeit a bit softer. Our evenings were spent wandering the iconic streets of New Orleans, with their famous balconies and lively atmosphere. The city’s unique blend of cultures and history made every moment unforgettable.</p>

<h2 id="jacksonville-missed-connections-and-meat-feasts">Jacksonville: Missed Connections and Meat Feasts</h2>

<p>Our road trip went on to Jacksonville, Florida. The plan was to reconnect with Will, a friend I had met in Taiwan years ago. Unfortunately, our schedules got tangled, and we missed each other by a day. It’s a bummer because I really liked the guy, but such is life. We haven’t been in touch since then, which is a bit sad.</p>

<p>However, Jacksonville wasn’t all about missed connections. Markus and I indulged in a Brazilian barbecue at <a href="https://terragaucha.com">Terra Gaucha</a> Brazilian Steakhouse. If you haven’t experienced a rodizio, let me paint a picture: waiters walk around with massive skewers of meat, slicing off pieces directly onto your plate until you flip a sign from green to red. The highlight for me was the grilled pineapple dessert, coated in sugar and cinnamon. It was a sweet ending to an otherwise uneventful stay in Jacksonville.</p>

<h2 id="southern-charm-at-cracker-barrel">Southern Charm at Cracker Barrel</h2>

<p>The next morning, we hit the road northward and stopped for breakfast at a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cracker_Barrel">Cracker Barrel</a> in Kingsland, Georgia. This place is a Southern US institution, serving hearty meals that are a bit too heavy for my taste. I tried to avoid the carb overload, but Markus had no such reservations. He drove for the next few hours while I battled a food coma.</p>

<p>Cracker Barrel also has a quirky store attached to it, selling everything from trucker hats to old-fashioned candies. It’s like stepping into a time capsule of Americana, and it’s worth a visit just for the novelty.</p>

<h2 id="savannah-a-brief-but-memorable-stop">Savannah: A Brief but Memorable Stop</h2>

<p>Our journey took us to Savannah, Georgia, a city that oozes Southern charm. We didn’t stay long, but we made the most of our time with an <a href="https://www.trolleytours.com/savannah">Old Town Trolley Tour</a>. The tour guide was entertaining, and the city’s historic architecture was captivating. Savannah’s old brick houses and cobblestone streets make it a picturesque stop, even if it’s just for a few hours.</p>

<h2 id="litchfield-beach-a-slice-of-artificial-paradise">Litchfield Beach: A Slice of Artificial Paradise</h2>

<p>From Savannah, we headed to Litchfield Beach, South Carolina, where we stayed at a country club. The place was meticulously maintained, with lush green lawns and an artificial lake. It felt like a retirement haven for wealthy Americans. Dinner at <a href="https://perronesmarket.com">Perrone’s Restaurant</a> and Bar was a highlight, featuring a hearty steak and lobster tail combo.</p>

<p>The next morning, we stumbled upon a quaint market that offered “German specialties.” It was a nostalgic touch, and the sandwiches we grabbed there were top-notch.</p>

<h2 id="exploring-the-outer-banks">Exploring the Outer Banks</h2>

<p>We didn’t linger in South Carolina and soon found ourselves in North Carolina, specifically the Outer Banks. This string of narrow, long islands stretches along the coast and offers a unique blend of natural beauty and laid-back vibes. Wilmington and Kure Beach were particularly memorable, with their relaxed beach town atmospheres.</p>

<p>One of the highlights was taking a ferry from <a href="https://www.fws.gov/refuge/cedar-island">Cedar Island</a> to <a href="https://www.visitocracokenc.com">Ocracoke</a>. This remote stretch of the Outer Banks is like stepping into another world. The ferry ride itself was an adventure, offering stunning views of the Atlantic Ocean.</p>

<h2 id="kitty-hawk-a-night-of-fun-and-culture">Kitty Hawk: A Night of Fun and Culture</h2>

<p>Our journey continued to Kitty Hawk, where we stayed in a charming Airbnb. The host welcomed us with a beer, and I took a quick dip in the Atlantic. Dinner at Longboards Grill was a bit of a letdown, but the evening took a turn for the better when we hit <a href="https://avalonpier.com">Avalon Pier</a>. The arcade games and the lively atmosphere made for a fun night.</p>

<p>Later, we wandered into a bar hosting a karaoke night. There, we met a semi-professional NASCAR driver who was the epitome of American culture. His mullet, trucker hat, and proud parents made for an interesting conversation. It was a fascinating glimpse into a world so different from ours.</p>

<h2 id="wrapping-up-in-king-of-prussia">Wrapping Up in King of Prussia</h2>

<p>After a night of fun in Kitty Hawk, we decided to head straight back to King of Prussia, Pennsylvania, where Markus lives. The drive was uneventful, but it felt good to be heading back to familiar territory. We spent the next few days relaxing, reminiscing about our trip, and indulging in some culinary adventures.</p>

<p>One of the highlights was a visit to a local deli at Chesterbrook Village Shopping Center, where I had the best pastrami sandwich of my life. Sadly, when we tried to revisit it a year later, it had closed down.</p>

<p>Before I left for Singapore, we also explored <a href="https://www.nps.gov/gett/index.htm">Gettysburg National Military Park</a>. This sprawling park offers a drive-through museum experience, taking you through historic battlefields and monuments. It’s a unique way to learn about American history.</p>

<p>We also visited an <a href="https://www.amishvillage.com">Amish village</a>, which was a fascinating peek into a simpler way of life.</p>

<h2 id="the-journey-home">The Journey Home</h2>

<p>Finally, on August 20th, I left from JFK Airport for an 18-hour flight back to Singapore. The flight was surprisingly comfortable, and I arrived home ready for my next adventure. But that’s a story for another time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Julian Lindner</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="americas" /><category term="usa" /><category term="usa" /><category term="road-trip" /><category term="mammoth-caves" /><category term="nashville" /><category term="memphis" /><category term="travel" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="friendship" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A journey through the eastern United States with my good friend Markus. Through the heart of America on the iconic Blue Ridge Parkway, filled with unexpected stops, breathtaking views, and unforgettable experiences.]]></summary></entry></feed>